Walid El Idrissi

IT Administrator / Junior Data Analyst

Experienced IT Administrator and Junior Data Analyst with over 4 years of expertise in the administration and maintenance of networks and IT systems. Actively seeking new professional challenges that will enable me to contribute my skills and evolve within a larger company.

+212-707-547-004 · walidelidrissi99@outlook.fr · Kasbat amine 3 IMM 9, Lissasfa, Casablanca, Morocco https://walidelidrissi.github.io/

EXPERIENCE

IT Administrator

DigitalPro-Sales - September 2022 - Now

- Install and configure software and hardware.
- Manage network servers and technology tools.
- · Troubleshoot issues and outages.
- Monitor performance and maintain systems according to requirements
- · Set up accounts and workstations
- Build an internal wiki with technical documentation, manuals and IT policies
- · Ensure security through access controls, backups and firewalls
- Develop expertise to train staff on new technologies

IT specialist

Cogitas Solutions - January 2022 - September 2022

- Hardware and Software installation, configuration and Issues Handling.
- Installation and configuration of operating systems(windows, linux).
- Installation and configuration of services (DNS,ADDS,FTP,DHCP,VPN....)
- Installation and configuration of fortigate and fortiapp.
- · Data recovery.
- · Software Testing.
- · Creation websites with wordpress.
- Cabling and patching
- Experience in ERP, CRM.
- Creation of process manuals, documentation/videos.
- · Graphic Design.

IT specialist

Marloc - September 2019 - December 2021

- Installing new software and hardware components.
- Regularly evaluating our IT systems to ensure they meet the necessary demands.
- · Assisting with network administration tasks.
- Resolving all issues coworkers have with their IT systems and software.
- Ensuring data storage is safe and secure.
- Educating coworkers about network security and best practices for computer usage.

EDUCATION

Data Analytics

African Leadership X 2023

Bachelor Degree in Systems, Networks and Security Engineering (SNSE)

Hassan I university 2020

Computer Network Technician Diploma

OFPPT - ISTA NTIC 2019

CERTIFICATION

Fortinet NSE 3 Certification Fortinet NSE 2 Certification Fortinet NSE 1 Certification

LANGUAGES

Arabic: Mother tongue English: Advanced C2 EF SET French: Average German: B1

SKILLS

Technical Skills:
Cisco - Cyber Security AWS(EC2,IAM,Aurora,SES) - VPN ADDS - DNS - DHCP - FTP Virtualization - Windows Server Linux - SQLServer - Wireless
technologies - HTML - CSS Wordpress - Infographics and graphic

design Soft Skills:

Problem Solving - Creative thinking -Quick Learning - Time Management -Teamwork - Pay attention to the small details